<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Webster</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark Webster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the personal site of Mark Webster, former Statistics postgraduate at University of Leeds (UK), now a Data Scientist at Visformatics. My current work is under wraps, but I aim to make this site a portfolio for older work and side projects. It&#39;s currently under construction. I&#39;m planning to migrate over my posts on my old blog. In the meantime, you can see them at the old Probability and Statistics blog, The Accidental Statistician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic work</title>
      <link>/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academic/</guid>
      <description>Until recently, I was working in academia. My undergraduate was in Mathematics, my postgraduate was in Statistics.
Thesis
Papers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>2016 CONVERGENCE PROPERTIES OF APPROXIMATE BAYESIAN COMPUTATION
PhD Thesis.
This looked at the rate of convergence for several versions of the ABC algorithm. Some of the results were also published in Barber et. al. 2015. The other main section looks at a new variants, which has a better rate of convergence for posterior mean estimation.
White Rose eTheses Online version
2015 THE RATE OF CONVERGENCE FOR APPROXIMATE BAYESIAN COMPUTATION
with Stuart Barber and Jochen Voss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis</title>
      <link>/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Approximate Bayesian Computation is a Monte Carlo method that is rather naïve, because in its basic form it does not use any assumptions about the distributions involved, outside of the prior densities and the model process. This naiveté results in computational inefficiency, but means ABC can be applied to problems that are not yet well understood enough for more sophisticated methods.
However, one complication is that the algorithm requires a tolerance parameter, which determines how forgiving it is about simulation data being different from the original observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codex game model</title>
      <link>/codex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/codex/</guid>
      <description>Codex is a card game by Sirlin Games. It is a non-collectible card game, that is a mix of Magic: The Gathering&#39;s combat mechanics, Dominion-like games&amp;rsquo; deck building, and a strategic layer themed around real-time strategy games, especially Warcraft III.
Official pages:
 Codex page at Sirlin Games, including links to articles on the game&#39;s design at David Sirlin&#39;s design blog. Official Sirlin Games forum  The game is played with decks consisting of three different &amp;ldquo;specs&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codex model</title>
      <link>/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/model/</guid>
      <description>Simulation configurationCurrent model sample size is 4000. However, since we use a Markov Chain sampler, the samples are correlated: the effective sample size varies between different parameters, within the range (1036, 8652).
Posterior model performance{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;/model_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_Matchup predictions for mean performance models.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}If the model predicted matches by saying the most likely winner would win, its performance on the above matches, which were used to fit it, would be 345 out of 403 (85.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>